Molin Zhang

molin@mit.edu

3 617-335-4072

in molin-zhang

http://molinzhang.github.io/

Biography

My name is Molin Zhang and I'm a fifth-year PhD student at Electrical Engineering and Computer Science at MIT working with Prof. Elfar Adalsteinsson.

My research centers on the intersection of computational imaging, computer vision, and signal processing, with a particular emphasis on medical imaging. I delve into the realm of inverse problems, utilizing numerical simulations to develop innovative solutions.

Employment History

06/2023 - 09/2023

Computational Camera Imaging Intern

Mobile Processor Innovation, Samsung Research America

Developed novel prototypes of memory-efficient AI-powered camera imaging pipelines, showcasing their tangible viability across diverse imaging applications such as image demosaicing, denoising, registration, and more.

06/2021 - 09/2021

AI/ML Research Intern

GE Healthcare

Designed and implemented an AI model utilizing Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) for the precise assessment of Leg Length Discrepancy (LLD) and angle measurement through X-ray image analysis. **Patent granted.**

Education

2021 - Now

Ph.D., Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

GPA: 5.0/5.0

Research focus: Computational imaging; Computer vision; Signal processing; Medical

imaging; Inverse problem; Numerical simulation **Supervisor:** Professor Elfar Adalsteinsson

2019 - 2021

M.Sc. Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Thesis title: A pipeline for zoomed fetal MRI.

2015 - 2019

B.S. Tsinghua University

Engineering Physics

GPA: 3.8/4.0. **Ranking:** 1st/140.

Research Project

04/2023 - Now

Multi-contrast super-resolution MR with generative AI

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, MIT, Prof. Elfar Adalsteinsson. Improving super-resolution performance by exploiting shared information among multi-contrast MR images to solve the inverse problem with diffusion model.

Research Project (continued)

06/2022 -08/2022

■ Uncertainty estimation with CRLB on quantitative MR with dictionary matching

Electrical Engineering, Stanford, Prof. Kawin Setsompop.

Optimized parameters of acquisition parameters based on the uncertainty estimation of quantitative MR with dictionary matching.

11/2021 -04/2022

Self-supervised inverse problem solving for MR reconstruction

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, MIT, Prof. Elfar Adalsteinsson.

Developed a novel self-supervised method for single MR data point reconstruction with the incorporation of linear subspace model.

09/2021 -02/2023

Novel selective MR pulse design with auto-differentiation

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, MIT, Prof. Elfar Adalsteinsson. Designed a novel pipeline for the optimization of MR excitation pulses with derived crusher gradient effect based on Fourier transform analysis and decomposition property of MR Bloch equation.

09/2019 -05/2021

Novel pose estimation techniques in MRI

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, MIT, Prof. Elfar Adalsteinsson. Exploited and developed methods with Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Deep Reinforcement Learning (DRL) for pose estimation in 3D fetal MRI.

Research Publications

Journal Articles

- Y. Arefeen, J. Xu, **M. Zhang**, et al., "Latent signal models: Learning compact representations of signal evolution for improved time-resolved, multi-contrast mri," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 2023.
- **M. Zhang**, Y. Arefeen, N. Arango, J. P. Stockmann, J. White, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Stochastic-offset-enhanced restricted slice excitation and 180° refocusing designs with spatially non-linear Δbo shim array fields.," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 2023.
- M. Zhang, N. Arango, J. P. Stockmann, J. White, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Selective rf excitation designs enabled by time-varying spatially non-linear Δ bo fields with applications in fetal mri," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, vol. 87, no. 5, pp. 2161–2177, 2022.

Conference Proceedings

- **M. Zhang**, J. Xu, Y. Arefeen, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Zero-shot self-supervised joint temporal image and sensitivity map reconstruction via linear latent space," in *Medical Imaging with Deep Learning*, 2023.
- J. Xu, **M. Zhang**, L. Vasung, et al., "An automated pose and motion estimation pipeline in dynamic 3d fetal mri," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 30th Scientific Meeting*, 2022.
- M. Zhang, Y. Arefeen, N. Arango, J. P. Stockmann, J. White, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Selective refocusing pulse design via time-varying nonlinear shim array fields and rf pulse with decomposition property," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 30th Scientific Meeting*, 2022.
- **M. Zhang**, J. Xu, Y. Arefeen, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Zero-shot self-supervised learning for 2d t2-shuffling mri reconstruction," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 30th Scientific Meeting*, 2022.

- M. Zhang, J. Xu, Y. Arefeen, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Inner volume excitation via joint design of time-varying nonlinear shim-array fields and rf pulse," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 29th Scientific Meeting*, 2021.
- J. Xu, M. Zhang, E. A. Turk, P. E. Grant, P. Golland, and E. Adalsteinsson, "3d fetal pose estimation with adaptive variance and conditional generative adversarial network," in Medical Ultrasound, and Preterm, Perinatal and Paediatric Image Analysis: First International Workshop, ASMUS 2020, and 5th International Workshop, PIPPI 2020, Held in Conjunction with MICCAI 2020, Lima, Peru, October 4-8, 2020, Proceedings 1, Springer, 2020, pp. 201–210.
- M. Zhang, J. Xu, E. Abaci Turk, P. E. Grant, P. Golland, and E. Adalsteinsson, "Enhanced detection of fetal pose in 3d mri by deep reinforcement learning with physical structure priors on anatomy," in Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention–MICCAI 2020: 23rd International Conference, Lima, Peru, October 4–8, 2020, Proceedings, Part VI 23, Springer, 2020, pp. 396–405.
- M. Zhang, J. Xu, E. Turk, et al., "Landmark detection of fetal pose in volumetric mri via deep reinforcement learning," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 28th Scientific Meeting*, 2020.
- J. Xu, **M. Zhang**, E. A. Turk, et al., "Fetal pose estimation in volumetric mri using a 3d convolution neural network," in *Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention–MICCAI 2019: 22nd International Conference, Shenzhen, China, October 13–17, 2019, Proceedings, Part IV 22, Springer, 2019, pp. 403–410.*
- **M. Zhang**, J. Xu, E. Turk, et al., "Fetal pose estimation via deep neural network by detection of fetal joints, eyes, and bladder," in *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 27th Scientific Meeting*, 2019.

Skills

Languages

English and Chinese.

Coding

Python and MATLAB

Domain knowledge

Computational Photography; Camera/ISP pipeline; Medical Imaging; Image processing; Image analysis; Pose estimation and tracking; Denoising; Demosaicing; Registration; Simulation; Inverse problem; Deep learning; Machine Learning; Reinforcement learning; MR pulse optimization; Tensorflow; Pytorch.

Miscellaneous Experience

Awards and Achievements

2019 Presidental Scholarship, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.

2018 National Scholarship, Tsinghua University.

Services

2023 **Reviewer**, MICCAI 2023.

Reviewer, AAAI workshop 2023.

References

Dr. Elfar Adalsteinsson

Professor
Electrical Engineering and Computer Scinece,
Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
elfar@mit.edu

Dr. Michael Polley

Senoir Vice President
Mobile Processor Innovation,
Samsung Research America.
mpolley@samsung.com